<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[Fang's Blog]]></title>
  
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.zhaoyf.net/"/>
  <updated>2015-10-31T18:05:02.168Z</updated>
  <id>http://www.zhaoyf.net/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Yuanfang Zhao]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[i have a dream]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.zhaoyf.net/2015/11/01/i-have-a-dream/"/>
    <id>http://www.zhaoyf.net/2015/11/01/i-have-a-dream/</id>
    <published>2015-10-31T18:05:02.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-10-31T18:05:02.168Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In 15 chapters, Acemoglu and Robinson try to examine which factors are responsible for the political and economical success or failure of states. They argue that the existing explanations about the emergence of prosperity and poverty, e.g. geography, climate, culture, religion or economic policies, are either insufficient or defective. They support their thesis by using countries as case studies, which are similar in all the mentioned factors but still developed differently in term of prosperity. The most incisive example is Korea, which was divided into North and South Korea 60 years ago and both countries’ economies have developed completely differently since then. Further examples are the border cities Nogales (Sonora, Mexico) and Nogales (Arizona, USA). By reference to border cities, the authors analyze the impact of the institutional environment on the prosperity of people from the same geographical area and same culture.</p>
<p>The major thesis of Acemoglu and Robinson is that economic prosperity depends above all on the inclusiveness of economic and political institutions. Only a functioning democratic and pluralistic state which guarantees the rule of law is able to exploit the ideas and talents, which are spread among the whole population of a nation. In extractive systems (autocracies) however, entrepreneurs `</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>In 15 chapters, Acemoglu and Robinson try to examine which factors are responsible for the political and economical success or failure of]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
